<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:distill="https://distill.pub/journal/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>The R Journal</title>
    <link>https://rjournal-distill.netlify.app/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://rjournal-distill.netlify.app/articles.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <description>Articles published in the R Journal</description>
    <image>
      <title>The R Journal</title>
      <url>https://rjournal-distill.netlify.app/resources/favicon.ico</url>
      <link>https://rjournal-distill.netlify.app/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Distill</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>stratamatch: Prognostic Score Stratification Using a Pilot Design</title>
      <dc:creator>Rachael C. Aikens</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Joseph Rigdon</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Justin Lee</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Michael Baiocchi</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Andrew B. Goldstone</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Peter Chiu</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Y. Joseph Woo</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jonathan H. Chen</dc:creator>
      <link>https://rjournal-distill.netlify.app/articles/RJ-2021-063</link>
      <description>Optimal propensity score matching has emerged as one of the most ubiquitous approaches
 for causal inference studies on observational data. However, outstanding critiques of the statistical
 properties of propensity score matching have cast doubt on the statistical efficiency of this technique,
 and the poor scalability of optimal matching to large data sets makes this approach inconvenient
 if not infeasible for sample sizes that are increasingly commonplace in modern observational data.
 The stratamatch package provides implementation support and diagnostics for ‘stratified matching
 designs,’ an approach that addresses both of these issues with optimal propensity score matching for
 large-sample observational studies. First, stratifying the data enables more computationally efficient
 matching of large data sets. Second, stratamatch implements a ‘pilot design’ approach in order to
 stratify by a prognostic score, which may increase the precision of the effect estimate and increase
 power in sensitivity analyses of unmeasured confounding.</description>
      <guid>https://rjournal-distill.netlify.app/articles/RJ-2021-063</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BayesSPsurv: An R Package to Estimate Bayesian (Spatial) Split-Population Survival Models</title>
      <dc:creator>Brandon Bolte</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Nicolás Schmidt</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Sergio Béjar</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Nguyen Huynh</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Bumba Mukherjee</dc:creator>
      <link>https://rjournal-distill.netlify.app/articles/RJ-2021-068</link>
      <description>Survival data often include a fraction of units that are susceptible to an event of interest
 as well as a fraction of “immune” units. In many applications, spatial clustering in unobserved risk
 factors across nearby units can also affect their survival rates and odds of becoming immune. To
 address these methodological challenges, this article introduces our BayesSPsurv R-package, which
 fits parametric Bayesian Spatial split-population survival (cure) models that can account for spatial
 autocorrelation in both subpopulations of the user’s time-to-event data. Spatial autocorrelation is
 modeled with spatially weighted frailties, which are estimated using a conditionally autoregressive
 prior. The user can also fit parametric cure models with or without nonspatial i.i.d. frailties, and
 each model can incorporate time-varying covariates. BayesSPsurv also includes various functions to
 conduct pre-estimation spatial autocorrelation tests, visualize results, and assess model performance,
 all of which are illustrated using data on post-civil war peace survival.</description>
      <guid>https://rjournal-distill.netlify.app/articles/RJ-2021-068</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ROCnReg: An R Package for Receiver Operating Characteristic Curve Inference With and Without Covariates</title>
      <dc:creator>María Xosé Rodríguez-Álvarez</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Vanda Inácio</dc:creator>
      <link>https://rjournal-distill.netlify.app/articles/RJ-2021-066</link>
      <description>This paper introduces the package ROCnReg that allows estimating the pooled ROC
 curve, the covariate-specific ROC curve, and the covariate-adjusted ROC curve by different methods,
 both from (semi) parametric and nonparametric perspectives and within Bayesian and frequentist
 paradigms. From the estimated ROC curve (pooled, covariate-specific, or covariate-adjusted), several
 summary measures of discriminatory accuracy, such as the (partial) area under the ROC curve and the
 Youden index, can be obtained. The package also provides functions to obtain ROC-based optimal
 threshold values using several criteria, namely, the Youden index criterion and the criterion that
 sets a target value for the false positive fraction. For the Bayesian methods, we provide tools for
 assessing model fit via posterior predictive checks, while the model choice can be carried out via
 several information criteria. Numerical and graphical outputs are provided for all methods. This is
 the only package implementing Bayesian procedures for ROC curves.</description>
      <guid>https://rjournal-distill.netlify.app/articles/RJ-2021-066</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The bdpar Package: Big Data Pipelining Architecture for R</title>
      <dc:creator>Miguel Ferreiro-Díaz</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Tomás R. Cotos-Yáñez</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>José R. Méndez</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>David Ruano-Ordás</dc:creator>
      <link>https://rjournal-distill.netlify.app/articles/RJ-2021-065</link>
      <description>In the last years, big data has become a useful paradigm for taking advantage of multiple
 sources to find relevant knowledge in real domains (such as the design of personalized marketing
 campaigns or helping to palliate the effects of several fatal diseases). Big data programming tools and
 methods have evolved over time from a MapReduce to a pipeline-based archetype. Concretely the use
 of pipelining schemes has become the most reliable way of processing and analyzing large amounts of
 data. To this end, this work introduces bdpar, a new highly customizable pipeline-based framework
 (using the OOP paradigm provided by R6 package) able to execute multiple preprocessing tasks over
 heterogeneous data sources. Moreover, to increase the flexibility and performance, bdpar provides
 helpful features such as (i) the definition of a novel object-based pipe operator (%&gt;|%), (ii) the ability to
 easily design and deploy new (and customized) input data parsers, tasks, and pipelines, (iii) only-once
 execution which avoids the execution of previously processed information (instances), guaranteeing
 that only new both input data and pipelines are executed, (iv) the capability to perform serial or
 parallel operations according to the user needs, (v) the inclusion of a debugging mechanism which
 allows users to check the status of each instance (and find possible errors) throughout the process.</description>
      <guid>https://rjournal-distill.netlify.app/articles/RJ-2021-065</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
